<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mennenia</title>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mennenia.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://www.mennenia.com</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Changing up the terminal</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently overhauled my terminal. I had a great setup when I was in university, because I relied on the command line a lot, but since doing iOS development I’ve let it slide. All I used it for was git, and the (by now) broken zsh configuration I had seemed to do the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to try the fish shell for ages, but it wasn’t until I saw it all come together in &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/daniel1of1&quot;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt;’s terminal that I finally set aside time to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-a-hotkey&quot;&gt;Setting up a hotkey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, easy access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to have a hotkey for a terminal window. That was the whole reason I used iTerm. Why did I even stop doing that?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iterm2.com&quot;&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt; if you’re not using it already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to preferences (cmd+, as always), “keys” tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on “Show/hide iTerm with a system-wide hotkey”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on the key (I use alt+space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would recommend getting a dedicated profile so you can dim the background appropriately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prettify to your liking under profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/itermpreferences.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the dimming - I like that you can still see bits of the background, hence I’ve got a dedicated profile where I can set the opacity of the background colour. You could also make it your default profile and it will most likely be solid, depending on what you normally use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/dimmedview.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fish&quot;&gt;Fish&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I felt there was more my shell should be doing for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;Fish&lt;/a&gt; suggest things as you type! This reminds me of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;product&lt;/a&gt; I used to work on, lol…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, fish predicts commands based on what you’ve typed previously, and you can autocomplete these with the right arrow (or left I suppose, if you’re computer is set to Right to Left? I never tried..).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing is easy if you have &lt;a href=&quot;http://brew.sh&quot;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;brew install fish&lt;/code&gt;, done! Don’t worry if you don’t have brew (although I would recommend it), more installation info can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;customised-themes&quot;&gt;Customised themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I like a pretty shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like zsh (which I’ve used the past 6 years), fish has an “oh my” version which allows for easy theming. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned, I blatantly copied Daniel and choose the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish/blob/master/docs/Themes.md#agnoster&quot;&gt;agnoster&lt;/a&gt; theme. Mainly because it has thick chunky bits of colour, and that made it very easy to read. I like it when the prompt is visually quite separate from the commands I will be typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/prompt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of colour, you can download iTerm profiles / colour schemes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish/blob/master/docs/Themes.md#agnoster&quot;&gt;this awesome site&lt;/a&gt;. It makes life so much easier! I went for n0tch2k, because I like that muted effect that still has some bright pastel colours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/mbadolato/iTerm2-Color-Schemes/raw/master/screenshots/n0tch2k.png&quot; alt=&quot;n0tch2k&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then finally, you need a “powerline font” for Agnoster to work well, or else the arrows won’t show up as expected. If you don’t have those, it may be that your prompt looks a bit like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/brokenprompt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fonts can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/powerline/fonts&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and there is a nice bash script to install them all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted for &lt;strong&gt;Hack&lt;/strong&gt;, and had the non-ASCII font set to a bit larger so that the arrows would match the coloured block precisely. I did this for both the default profile and the hotkey window, by the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/fontsettings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. I know there’s plenty more customisation that you can do, and I might explore that in the future, but for now I’m glad that I have an easily accessible, smart, and pretty shell to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“NaBloWriMo”</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-01-nablowrimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-01-nablowrimo/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;nanowrimo-blog-edition&quot;&gt;NaNoWriMo - Blog edition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve keenly followed &lt;a href=&quot;http://nanowrimo.org&quot;&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/a&gt; (National Novel Writing Month) since I was fourteen or so, but never participated. I didn’t have ideas for a novel, I was too busy, something unexpected came up, you name it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to change it up a bit. Instead of worrying about a novel, I’d tackle another writing project I’ve been wanting to get around to for &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt;. My blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having had an on-and-off blog for as long as I can remember, it’s been too long without one. I briefly dabbled in a new wordpress one earlier this year (with too many unreleased posts), until &lt;a href=&quot;http://honzadvorsky.com&quot;&gt;Honza&lt;/a&gt; convinced me that something light and simple like &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io&quot;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt; was really the way forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t just about the tools though. What I realised put me off blogging for so long is that whenever I read something back, it just didn’t seem right. You know that feeling when you hear yourself back on a recording? And your voice just sounds &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt;? That’s what I have every. single. time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, welcome November 2015. The month where I, hopefully, find my writing voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nablowrimo-the-rules&quot;&gt;NaBloWriMo - The Rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NaNoWriMo has a simple definition: one month, 50,000 words. Oh, and it should be fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will National Blog Writing Month be about? I eventually settled on the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write at least one paragraph each day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish a post every week (so you end up with four at the end of the month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;styling&quot;&gt;Styling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with the basics, don’t change anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweak one thing a day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Designed to not take more than half an hour a day, it’s all about being set up for succes. A challenge we should all be able to take on, right? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re really keen, tweet (&lt;code&gt;#NaBloWriMo&lt;/code&gt;) letting the world know you wrote your paragraph for the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-start&quot;&gt;How to start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a blog on a platform of your choosing. Edit the &lt;em&gt;bare minimum&lt;/em&gt;. Delete the boilerplate posts, change the title, and maybe, just maybe, change the background colour. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then focus on publishing one post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one post could be anything. An introduction to yourself. The reason why you’d like to blog. A tour of the city you currently live in and your favourite restaurants. What you had for dinner last night. Pictures of your dog. It doesn’t matter. What matters is that you write down some words and share them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it’s this one. And hopefully one that will inspire you to join me in this challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>