<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mennenia</title>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mennenia.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://www.mennenia.com</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Making a visionboard in Sketch</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-12-23-sketchtutorial-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-12-23-sketchtutorial-board/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly, thank you to everyone who’s reached out to me in the past 24 hours. I never expected such overwhelming support. To those of you who have experienced very similar things, I hope it helps to know you’re not alone - it’s the whole reason I decided to publish &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-12-23-goodbye2015/&quot;&gt;yesterday’s post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second most common thing I heard was: “That visionboard is really neat! How do I make one?” So I made a screencast to show you how. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-make-a-grid-of-cool-images-in-sketch&quot;&gt;How to make a grid of cool images in Sketch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually already made my 2016 board a few days ago, so it was easy for me to film the process. The screencast will walk you through all the steps. You’ll get a sneak peak of my next post: my goals for next year! 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WSnW_duDh-A&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/WSnW_duDh-A/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screencast&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially you need a bunch of images that you’d like to use and you think represent whichever goals you have. I often use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, but have also been known to dip into &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also create your own from your own photography or from combining your favourite quotes and typography using a host of different apps: &lt;a href=&quot;http://madewithover.com&quot;&gt;Over&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://post.adobe.com&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/a&gt;, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then used Sketch to make it into the full image you’ll see featured on the blog shortly. Essentially I calculate the size of each image, and then create rectangles for each. These will mask the images, once I start incorporating those. Easy! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-goals&quot;&gt;Setting goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a big believer of setting goals and having constant reminders of them. I feel like New Years Resolutions have gotten a bad rep, but that is often because they don’t last very long. People take on too many things at the same time, and burn out from them just a few weeks in. No wonder they’re considered a joke. The practice of setting them, and improving on yourself isn’t though! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I tend to do with these boards is put in a few daily rituals that I would like to shape, for instance meditating regularly. The visual representation reminds me of it throughout the year, so I don’t forget to try and do it as often as I can. Surely, it may not be every day, but at least I’m still working on it come June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing I urge you to consider are some goals you can easily tick off or where the result is obvious. For instance, getting a driver’s license or going to a specific country. Once you’ve done that, you can see how you’re starting to make progress. It also means that you don’t have to focus on all of these right now. I have the reminder that at some point in the year I want to take driving lessons, but it doesn’t have to be January. It could be July. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also why I like to put 23 goals down: they’re supposed to last the whole year and they’re supposed to be a bit of a stretch. I’d rather fail a few, but have completed most, than setting myself only 6, say. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take from this what you will, but it’s worked for me for quite a while ☺️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you end up making any, I’d love to see them. Let’s make 2016 an awesome year for self-improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye 2015, Hello 2016</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-12-23-goodbye2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-12-23-goodbye2015/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I intended on writing a “thoughts on the year” when I decided to blog again just a few weeks ago, but gosh, has a lot changed since then again. This is gonna be a long one - brace yourselves :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2015&quot;&gt;2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll start right off the bat and say that 2015 was not a great year. Don’t get me wrong, a lot of good things happened, but personally I’ve just not felt that great and here’s a little bit on why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year started off pretty decent, as I (and the people I worked with I’m sure) had a much needed, long Christmas break. In 2014 we had a massive crunch time project, trying to ship &lt;a href=&quot;https://swiftkey.com/en/keyboard/ios&quot;&gt;SwiftKey for iOS&lt;/a&gt;, and I don’t think we managed to allow ourselves to take a breather until the end of the year. I went to the USA and hung out with my family. It was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came back to work with renewed energy, but found myself loosing that energy very quickly. Many things around me were changing, and for some reason it got to me. Maybe it was work, maybe I was long overdue another episode, but I found myself getting more and more depressed again. So much so, that around April our wonderful head of HR told me to go home. “Don’t worry about it, just focus on yourself. Just take some time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a relief hearing this from your employer, when you try so hard to do the best you can at work and often feel like you can’t show any weakness. I took this week to think about what it is that I wanted to do. Maybe it was time for a shift in my day to day. Up until this point, I had been doing more design work, and had been asking for it also, but what if I could somehow formalise it more? Structure it better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What that requires though, is an understanding and acceptance that someone can genuinely do both crafts to a certain standard. This is something that is, I think, still hard to swallow for many. And for me, at that point, I felt like I could no longer choose between engineering and design. If anything, I was leaning more and more to doing design full time because there was a point where I felt I lost any faith in myself being a decent engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I’ve ever been depressed while in a work environment. It wasn’t high school, it wasn’t uni. I couldn’t give myself the break I needed and then make up for lost time by hitting exams hard. I couldn’t avoid people. Instead, I had to come into work every day and face stand-up. Never had I come to hate an agile practice more. How do you say “I felt absolute rubbish yesterday and barely managed to get out of bed let alone be productive. Oh and today isn’t much better”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So started a completely new chapter of my life. Anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I had to continuously keep up appearances at work, so I over-promised on things, and worked myself into the ground trying to complete them despite feeling depressed. This meant there were no evenings anymore. No weekends anymore. Just continuous guilt over trying to finish something that &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be a simple task. And the more this happened, the more I started believing that clearly it was me - I was no longer capable of writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in this cycle of avoidance, pressure, and sadness, my body gave up. I had been feeling chest pains for a long while already, but I didn’t know I was genuinely experiencing anxiety symptoms. At some point in June, I had a panic attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don’t know what panic attacks are, they are in all honesty pretty harmless. But they are terrifying when you’re in them. You feel like you’ve lost all control over your body. Your body goes into full fright or flight mode, and I found myself shaking, crying, and hyper ventilating for well over an hour. You’re not dying and you know it, but you feel like you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My boyfriend tried to keep me calm over the phone while a good friend rushed over to my place to take me to A&amp;amp;E (on recommendation of my GP). After what, retrospectively, turned out to be a pretty hilarious few hours in hospital (we ordered Deliveroo!), I was literally given a chill pill and told that I should really take a break from work. Not only that, this was something I now needed to “manage”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt pretty broken. Anything and everything started affecting me. As I have quoted to many already, it got to a point that Tesco could’ve run out of spinach and tears would start welling up in my eyes. I just could no longer handle the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided I needed a change. A lot had changed at work, and it no longer seemed like the right fit. I was offered another job that I was quite excited about and I decided to take the leap. Making these changes (and more) felt great, because I felt like I was in control again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now comes the part that’s probably the hardest for me to talk about. I ignored my instincts and it got me into a pretty shitty situation. The new job didn’t feel right, not from day one. I had read &lt;a href=&quot;https://ashfurrow.com/blog/5-years-of-ios/&quot;&gt;Ash’s post&lt;/a&gt; and remember how he once quit upon starting. I desperately wanted to, but because everything that had happened this year I declared that it must’ve been me. I ignored how I felt, and pushed forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started on a new codebase, a new challenge, and it was amazing. I found such joy in development again and if there’s one thing I take away from this it’s that. And I am immensely grateful for it. Turns out I’m actually a pretty decent engineer, at least, more so than I thought of myself 4 months prior. Faith in myself returned and I was doing great again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I couldn’t get on board with is just about everything else. The way things were done and run were just not what I had imagined, nor what I was told to expect. I figured that a lot of it was because it was a small and young place. Friends of mine had faced the challenge of being in a startup, surely this couldn’t be any different. I spoke up. I tried to stand up for what I believed in and affect positive change. But it seemed as if the more I did that, the more things went in the opposite direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just two months in, I decided to quit. I felt like I was giving up, but after everything this year, I felt that I could no longer work in a place where the culture was so out of touch with how I saw things. It just wasn’t worth the dread of going into work. There were other places I could contribute to in a much healthier way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never, ever, did I expect to face the backlash I did when I announced my resignation (whilst still on probation period - that’s what they’re for right?). I was aware that this would not be great for them and I wanted to work together on a good outcome. But they made things personal, and that was just a blow below the belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had come quite far in getting better. My therapist, who makes me fill out some point based survey every time I see her, said that before this I was essentially considered “recovered”. After this I scored the worst I had until date. Eventually I had a panic attack on the tube. I somehow managed to get above ground, find a corner on a street, and break down until my boyfriend came running to find me and take me home. He has been amazing in all of this. This was the second time I had a panic attack, and hopefully the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My GP suggested medication and I, after giving it quite some thought, refused. Earlier this year it was me. I was feeling terrible and I was putting myself through unnecessary anxiety. It could’ve made sense then. This time around, it was not me. It was circumstantial and I trust myself to never ever put myself in this kind of situation again. I can’t tell you how proud I am that I had the guts to quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leads me to the good of 2015, because I promise you, there is quite a lot of that too! The above may have been the dominating theme, but actually, a whole host of things were absolutely awesome.  A lot of that is thanks to the fact that I reminded myself of it every day: I had a small “visionboard” on my phone’s lock screen. Let’s take a look at what I did managed to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-12-23-goodbye2015/2015iphone.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assembled visual representations of various personal goals I had for this year (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/mennenia/&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; was a useful source of imagery), to remind me long after most new year’s resolutions have been forgotten. I purposefully didn’t make them massively centered around work. I wanted them to be about random things I was interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From left to right, top to bottom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go lie on a beach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to WWDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Paris with my mum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the most out of sunny days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master the pidgeon pose in yoga&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get into drinking my green juices again (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PeterHolc/status/570540664200540160&quot;&gt;“Swamp Juice”&lt;/a&gt; as my fellow SwiftKeyers would call it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Envision and going after what I want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designing and shipping a native icon library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being less afraid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing to respond with kindness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put effort into what I wear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Berlin again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a panting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get back into photography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See at least one friend from a different continent that I hadn’t in a while&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work more on illustrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shut up and listen more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a 5k run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be more spontaneous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go somewhere alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get back into cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putting effort into what I want to get better at&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-lie-on-a-beach-&quot;&gt;Go lie on a beach ✅😍&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Dubai to visit a friend and we went to the beach! It was sooo relaxing. I ended up going by myself a few times too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-to-wwdc-&quot;&gt;Go to WWDC ✅😆&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to simply partake in the lottery and otherwise go anyway. There is usually so much &lt;a href=&quot;http://altconf.com&quot;&gt;going on&lt;/a&gt; in SF that time of year, that it’s well worth just hanging out. This year however, Apple opened up their scholarship to women also. I spent a pretty solid 36 hours writing the submission app and was awarded a free ticket to WWDC. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mostgood/status/607714269522620416&quot;&gt;Say what?!&lt;/a&gt; Definitely one of the highlights of the year, not to mention I got to meet &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/607671952040423425&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; and listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KwpKoi5Nbxk&quot;&gt;The Weeknd live&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/czechboy0&quot;&gt;Honza&lt;/a&gt; had to keep me from bouncing off my chair).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-to-paris-with-my-mum-&quot;&gt;Go to Paris with my mum ❌😔&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this didn’t work out, as I was travelling so much this year already. Quite gutted, but we’re trying to work things out for next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-the-most-out-of-sunny-days-&quot;&gt;Make the most out of sunny days ✅😊&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to all the “not wanting to leave the house”, I feel like I didn’t make use of the summer as much as I would’ve otherwise, but I still spent a good deal outdoors and on our patio. I love the feel of sun on my skin, and I think that I did experience that a decent amount this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;master-the-pidgeon-pose-pidgey-in-yoga-&quot;&gt;Master the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yogajournal.com/pose/one-legged-king-pigeon-pose/&quot;&gt;pidgeon pose&lt;/a&gt; in yoga ❌😠😭&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know that feeling when you roll out your mat, you stare at it, you do one or two poses and you just end up in child’s pose not wanting to do anything else? That has been me all year. 2014 was a fantastic yoga year, 2015 was not. I am making it a top priority for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-into-drinking-my-green-juices-again-&quot;&gt;Get into drinking my green juices again ✅👌&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this a lot. It’s still not every single day (keeping the supply of spinach incoming isn’t always easy), but a lot of what I have consumed this year has been in the form of green coloured juices and smoothies. Nom!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;practice-gratitude-&quot;&gt;Practice gratitude ✅☺️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contribute my overall “being cheery” to this and I believe it’s what kept me going this year. A lot of things have been wonderful and I am immensely thankful for it. I think it’s quite telling when, whilst being depressed, almost everyone on my SwiftKey leaving card wrote that my positive energy and attitude is what will be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;envision-and-going-after-what-i-want-&quot;&gt;Envision and going after what I want ✅🙂&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I was filled with doubt, I think I managed to have the sense to look at what needed changing and taking the leap(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;designing-and-shipping-a-native-icon-library-&quot;&gt;Designing and shipping a native icon library ❌❓😯&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A project I’ve been wanting to work on for a long time. It means combining my love for code and design, as well as just making my first pod. I am &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to get the simplest version of it out before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;being-less-afraid-&quot;&gt;Being less afraid ✅🙂&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, I think this worked out pretty well. My body has never felt this scared in my life, yet my mind is slowly becoming more and more resilient than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;choosing-to-respond-with-kindness-&quot;&gt;Choosing to respond with kindness - 🤔&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to think I’ve done this. I have received quite some positive feedback, though I’m sure I’ve managed to piss people off also. Some of these things are continuous journeys. I could be kinder to myself however, and in the last few months I have tried to make improvements there also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;put-effort-into-what-i-wear-&quot;&gt;Put effort into what I wear ✅😎&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cleared out my closet, leaving only choice pieces that all fit together properly. I don’t even need to think twice about getting dressed in the morning and feel good in just about everything I own. Absolute win, if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-to-berlin-again-&quot;&gt;Go to Berlin again ✅😊&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin holds a special place in my heart and it was great being there again. Even more so, because I was asked to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSnUt9ZfslM&quot;&gt;speak at UIKonf&lt;/a&gt;! Whilst not my best talk (in my opinion), it seemed to definitely be one of my best received talks :). It talks a lot about the struggle of being stuck between design and development, and it hopes to point out something I feel strongly about in our industry: this idea that one aspect of making a product can be considered “better” than others - something I fundamentally disagree with. I remember being a bit nervous about going out there and calling us developers a bunch of arrogant people. The audience was amazing however, and seemed to be fine with it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2015-&quot;&gt;2015.. ✅😅&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made it through the year I guess? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-a-panting-&quot;&gt;Make a panting ✅😃&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a live drawing class this year, and made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/579329667779395585&quot;&gt;sketch&lt;/a&gt; (nswf) I was pretty happy with! In general, I’ve gotten more into painting again. I’m still trying to dedicate more time to it, but it’s headed in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-back-into-photography-&quot;&gt;Get back into photography ❌😕&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from this one picture I took this year that I’m pleased with, I basically didn’t pick up my DSLR at all. I’m now at a stage where I’m not sure whether to sell it, or give it another go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;see-at-least-one-friend-from-a-different-continent-that-i-hadn-t-in-a-while-&quot;&gt;See at least one friend from a different continent that I hadn’t in a while ✅💯😄&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a friend in Dubai, another one in California, another in Berlin, another from Amsterdam, and one of my favourite people is visiting from Canada in a few days. This year has been great for seeing my besties from all around the world. I am so happy to have them in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-more-on-illustrations-&quot;&gt;Work more on illustrations ✅🙂&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I didn’t design and print an illustration to hang on a wall (as was my intention), I did get into creating more and more visual pieces. From checklists, to roadmaps, to icons, to scenery, to processes, it’s lowered the barrier of opening Sketch / Affinity Designer and just making what’s in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;shut-up-and-listen-more-&quot;&gt;Shut up and listen more ✅❓😶&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone that knows me in real life, I talk. A lot. I’d like to think that I’m pretty interactive when I chat and also listen, but still. I talk a lot. Considering I have always been like this (my mum got me &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/138128.Little_Miss_Chatterbox&quot;&gt;“Little Miss Chatterbox”&lt;/a&gt; when I was four), I think I took a step in the right direction for improving it. I did try and listen more actively this year. The funny thing with that is, you start to realise how not a lot of people always make sense… So in turn I’ve been trying to be more concrete in what message I try to deliver to others and just get to the point more often. It’s a work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-a-5k-run-&quot;&gt;Do a 5k run ✅😀&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/655719743836528640&quot;&gt;Did it&lt;/a&gt;. Not in the time I had originally set for myself, but then again, I didn’t train. That’s okay. I still turned up to the race and I ran. And it felt &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-more-spontaneous-&quot;&gt;Be more spontaneous ✅☺️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s how I choose to interpret this quote at least. I did some really fun and wild things this year. I somehow felt like I did more of it the year before, but that’s okay. It led me to experience great times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-somewhere-alone-&quot;&gt;Go somewhere alone ✅❓😯&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year I didn’t manage to get in a full solo trip, but I did travel to Dubai to see my friend who was often working, so a good chunk of that trip was just me. I went to Italy on my own for Pragma, but then some of that was spent with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ashfurrow&quot;&gt;awesome&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/orta&quot;&gt;friends&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chriseidhof&quot;&gt;from&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/icanzilb&quot;&gt;around&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iwasleeg&quot;&gt;the world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-back-into-cooking-&quot;&gt;Get back into cooking ✅😉&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve made some pretty awesome things this year, the highlight of which has been my most recent “brownie cookies”. Yes, they are as amazing as they sound! I saw a lot of myself in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hlLhtWLghGA&quot;&gt;Ash’s Pragma talk&lt;/a&gt;, where he describes the road to expertise. There are a lot of things that I’m decent at, I’m trying to get better at, and I just plain suck at. Cooking is one of those that I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; I’m great at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;putting-effort-into-what-i-want-to-get-better-at-&quot;&gt;Putting effort into what I want to get better at ✅😊&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think if anything, this is something I continued striving for and something that I have been most proud of. I may have felt like there were times when I threw in the towel, but I don’t think I did. The easy route is to complain, and I think I consciously choose to instead try and improve what I could. Myself, my health, my career, my relationships, and so forth. I am lucky that my friends also describe me as someone who doesn’t give up. It’s reassuring to know I can count on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;great-things-that-weren-t-on-the-board-but-still-happened-&quot;&gt;Great things that weren’t on the board, but still happened:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking at AltConf, iOSDevUK, BeyondConf and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosting &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/652424847864279041&quot;&gt;my first workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving in with my boyfriend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiking and sauna-ing in Switzerland &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/steipete/status/614519187298385921&quot;&gt;with friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/596388642098151425&quot;&gt;Poland with the iOS team&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chetbox/status/600321379607683073&quot;&gt;random shits and giggles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being back &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/672761120311140352&quot;&gt;in Edinburgh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be taken on a surprise birthday trip to my favourite spa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attending two cocktail courses - I now know a lot about rum and gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practicing mindfulness and meditations regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogging again (even though I didn’t complete &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-01-nablowrimo/&quot;&gt;NaNoWriBlo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-10-firstpodcast/&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stand by the fact that, in many ways, I had an amazing year. I developed as a person. Shit happens, yet life goes on. I still have all my loved ones in my life, which at the end of the day is all that matters to me - they are irreplaceable. A huge shout out to them for supporting me along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have great plans for 2016, and a new board is in the making. I will however spare you any more text and post it separately. If you managed to read all the way till the end - thank you :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope your year was lovely, and wishing you all the best for the next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays,
Maxim&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first podcast</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-10-firstpodcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-10-firstpodcast/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something very exciting happened a few weeks ago. I recorded my first podcast! I was interviewed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ameliahumfress&quot;&gt;Amelia&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.steer.me&quot;&gt;Steer&lt;/a&gt; for their upcoming conference &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beyondconf.co&quot;&gt;Beyond&lt;/a&gt;, as I’ll be speaking on Usability Testing there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s out now, and you can listen to it &lt;a href=&quot;http://beyondconf.co/an-interview-with-maxim-cramer/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;recording&quot;&gt;Recording&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recording a podcast is quite an interesting and surreal experience. After having recorded it, I couldn’t remember what it was that I said at all. And even weirder was that I experienced this feeling of “stage fright” &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; having recorded it. I think because I knew I wouldn’t be able to change anything anymore, and other people would be listening to it? Very odd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, it’s all done. I’m actually quite happy with it! They edited out one or two gaps of silence and a side comment here or there, but in all honesty, the way you hear it was pretty much how it was recorded. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;shownotes&quot;&gt;Shownotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to add some additional show notes. For those of you that listened to it and are new to iOS, allow me to expand on some of the things I said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many! Building for a device can be quite different to building for web, say. But the community is lovely, and has thankfully taken the time to document their knowledge, trials, and errors carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/&quot;&gt;Apple WWDC Videos&lt;/a&gt; - See these as “Apple University”, where they take you though all the available API they create for developers and how to use and leverage them. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/swift/resources/&quot;&gt;Official Swift Resources&lt;/a&gt; - All about helping you get started with Swift&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/Swift_Programming_Language/&quot;&gt;Official Swift Docs&lt;/a&gt; - Tells you all about the language. Available on the iBooks store for free also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official Class Docs - The language is separate from the framework Apple provides to leverage what the OS has to offer. Always consult the docs on how to’s and best practices! Example of UIView (to display things) &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UIKit/Reference/UIView_Class/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.objc.io/issues/&quot;&gt;Objc.io&lt;/a&gt; - Purposefully written content by industry experts on all major topics in iOS development. Excellent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nshipster.com&quot;&gt;NSHipster&lt;/a&gt; - Interesting content. If you’re discovering quirks and oddities about iOS / Mac development, chances are you’ll find a post about that exact issue here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iosdevweekly.com&quot;&gt;iOSDevWeekly&lt;/a&gt; - A weekly curated newsletter rounding up interesting blog articles on iOS development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://swiftnews.curated.co&quot;&gt;This week in Swift&lt;/a&gt; - Another great curated newsletter, focussing on Swift specifically. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user20904333/videos/page:1/sort:date&quot;&gt;NSLondon Videos&lt;/a&gt; - The London meetup I mentioned. It has been running for a long time and thus collected a great deal of community shared information, tips, and tricks — all recorded. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source Code - One of the best ways to learn is to see how others do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find local meetups near you. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com&quot;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; is a fantastic resource for getting to know the local scene. Also, head to Twitter and you’ll find plenty there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leveraging the community is one of the best things you can do, because you realise you’re not alone in your struggles. Developing code comes with its own set of quirks that takes some time to figure out and get used to. None of us worked it all out overnight! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can also be a very inspiring experience. I remember my first WWDC, my first meetup, and it made a significant difference in how I continued to approach my work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-at-your-own-pace&quot;&gt;Go at your own pace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t feel like you have to conquer everything in one go. I still don’t know every single API or “domain”. For example, I have a lot of experience with keyboards from my time at SwiftKey, but I’ve not done much with the camera (whereas, likely, someone who works on Instagram has). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mention in the podcast: it’s easy to feel like you should know everything and if you don’t, you should work on acquiring this knowledge day and night. Yes, curiosity is fantastic. Yes, studying the ins and outs of iOS development is good. But running on no sleep and experiencing stress on a daily basis isn’t. Take a deep breath. Do what works &lt;em&gt;for you&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a big thank you to those who’ve already shared it, tweeted it, and so forth. It means a lot :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing up the terminal</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently overhauled my terminal. I had a great setup when I was in university, because I relied on the command line a lot, but since doing iOS development I’ve let it slide. All I used it for was git, and the (by now) broken zsh configuration I had seemed to do the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to try the fish shell for ages, but it wasn’t until I saw it all come together in &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/daniel1of1&quot;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt;’s terminal that I finally set aside time to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-a-hotkey&quot;&gt;Setting up a hotkey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, easy access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to have a hotkey for a terminal window. That was the whole reason I used iTerm. Why did I even stop doing that?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iterm2.com&quot;&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt; if you’re not using it already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to preferences (cmd+, as always), “keys” tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on “Show/hide iTerm with a system-wide hotkey”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on the key (I use alt+space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would recommend getting a dedicated profile so you can dim the background appropriately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prettify to your liking under profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/itermpreferences.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the dimming - I like that you can still see bits of the background, hence I’ve got a dedicated profile where I can set the opacity of the background colour. You could also make it your default profile and it will most likely be solid, depending on what you normally use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/dimmedview.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fish&quot;&gt;Fish&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I felt there was more my shell should be doing for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;Fish&lt;/a&gt; suggest things as you type! This reminds me of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;product&lt;/a&gt; I used to work on, lol…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, fish predicts commands based on what you’ve typed previously, and you can autocomplete these with the right arrow (or left I suppose, if you’re computer is set to Right to Left? I never tried..).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing is easy if you have &lt;a href=&quot;http://brew.sh&quot;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;brew install fish&lt;/code&gt;, done! Don’t worry if you don’t have brew (although I would recommend it), more installation info can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;customised-themes&quot;&gt;Customised themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I like a pretty shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like zsh (which I’ve used the past 6 years), fish has an “oh my” version which allows for easy theming. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned, I blatantly copied Daniel and choose the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish/blob/master/docs/Themes.md#agnoster&quot;&gt;agnoster&lt;/a&gt; theme. Mainly because it has thick chunky bits of colour, and that made it very easy to read. I like it when the prompt is visually quite separate from the commands I will be typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/prompt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of colour, you can download iTerm profiles / colour schemes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish/blob/master/docs/Themes.md#agnoster&quot;&gt;this awesome site&lt;/a&gt;. It makes life so much easier! I went for n0tch2k, because I like that muted effect that still has some bright pastel colours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/mbadolato/iTerm2-Color-Schemes/raw/master/screenshots/n0tch2k.png&quot; alt=&quot;n0tch2k&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then finally, you need a “powerline font” for Agnoster to work well, or else the arrows won’t show up as expected. If you don’t have those, it may be that your prompt looks a bit like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/brokenprompt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fonts can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/powerline/fonts&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and there is a nice bash script to install them all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted for &lt;strong&gt;Hack&lt;/strong&gt;, and had the non-ASCII font set to a bit larger so that the arrows would match the coloured block precisely. I did this for both the default profile and the hotkey window, by the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2015-11-08-terminalsetup/fontsettings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. I know there’s plenty more customisation that you can do, and I might explore that in the future, but for now I’m glad that I have an easily accessible, smart, and pretty shell to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“NaBloWriMo”</title>
      <link>http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-01-nablowrimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mennenia.com/articles/2015-11-01-nablowrimo/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;nanowrimo-blog-edition&quot;&gt;NaNoWriMo - Blog edition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve keenly followed &lt;a href=&quot;http://nanowrimo.org&quot;&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/a&gt; (National Novel Writing Month) since I was fourteen or so, but never participated. I didn’t have ideas for a novel, I was too busy, something unexpected came up, you name it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to change it up a bit. Instead of worrying about a novel, I’d tackle another writing project I’ve been wanting to get around to for &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt;. My blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having had an on-and-off blog for as long as I can remember, it’s been too long without one. I briefly dabbled in a new wordpress one earlier this year (with too many unreleased posts), until &lt;a href=&quot;http://honzadvorsky.com&quot;&gt;Honza&lt;/a&gt; convinced me that something light and simple like &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io&quot;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt; was really the way forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t just about the tools though. What I realised put me off blogging for so long is that whenever I read something back, it just didn’t seem right. You know that feeling when you hear yourself back on a recording? And your voice just sounds &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt;? That’s what I have every. single. time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, welcome November 2015. The month where I, hopefully, find my writing voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nablowrimo-the-rules&quot;&gt;NaBloWriMo - The Rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NaNoWriMo has a simple definition: one month, 50,000 words. Oh, and it should be fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will National Blog Writing Month be about? I eventually settled on the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write at least one paragraph each day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish a post every week (so you end up with four at the end of the month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;styling&quot;&gt;Styling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with the basics, don’t change anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweak one thing a day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Designed to not take more than half an hour a day, it’s all about being set up for succes. A challenge we should all be able to take on, right? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re really keen, tweet (&lt;code&gt;#NaBloWriMo&lt;/code&gt;) letting the world know you wrote your paragraph for the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-start&quot;&gt;How to start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a blog on a platform of your choosing. Edit the &lt;em&gt;bare minimum&lt;/em&gt;. Delete the boilerplate posts, change the title, and maybe, just maybe, change the background colour. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then focus on publishing one post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one post could be anything. An introduction to yourself. The reason why you’d like to blog. A tour of the city you currently live in and your favourite restaurants. What you had for dinner last night. Pictures of your dog. It doesn’t matter. What matters is that you write down some words and share them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it’s this one. And hopefully one that will inspire you to join me in this challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>